DARIAN YANE

PROFILE

Data Analyst, MBA and **Bachelor's Degree in Economics**

Functional and business analyst with more than 20 years of experience in banking, pharmaceutical, power generation and investment industries.

Analytical, organized, and highly resolutive profile.

The training and experience in various areas and industries, allows me to have a deep analysis of business needs, providing added value beyond data analysis.

SKILLS

Economics Finance

Investments **Statistics**

Mathematics Logic

Administration **Business**

Power Query Power BI

Excel (with Macros) Python

Django SQL

Pandas Numpy

Matplotlib **CSS**

IMTH GIT

CONTACT

🛍 🛚 Mar del Plata, Argentina

(+54) 11-5311-7020

yanedarian.dev@gmail.com



darianyane.com



github.com/DarianYane



linkedin.com/in/darian-yane/

WORK EXPERIENCE

PYTHON TUTOR, CODERHOUSE

12/2022 - currently

INVESTMENT ANALYST/EDITOR, INVERSOR GLOBAL

09/2021 - 01/2023

Research Analyst on traditional stock market investments and cryptocurrencies.

PROFESSOR "CRYPTOCURRENCIES AND FINTECH", CODERHOUSE

08/2022 - 10/2022

FREELANCER (EXCEL), FIVERR

01-2021 - 09/2021

TEAM LEADER ACCOUNTS PAYABLE (AP), AES SERVICIOS AMÉRICA 01/2019 - 08/2020

Reports of industry metrics using SAP, Excel, Power Query and

Process automation with Excel Macros.

You can see the rest of my professional experience at linkedin.com/in/darian-yane/

EDUCATION

PYTHON, CODERHOUSE, 2022

MASTER'S DEGREE IN BUSINESS ADMINISTRATION (MBA, UADE, 2020

Distinction: MAGNA CUM LAUDE

Average: 8,68 (2nd best course average)

BACHELOR'S DEGREE IN ECONOMICS, UBA, 2011

ECONOMIC ACTUARY, (abandoned, 27 subjects passed)

AWARDS

1st Place Tournament "ACBSP - Company Game", Company Game, 2019

Member of the Argentine Team that participated in the 9th Southern Cone Olympiad, Argentine Mathematical Olympiad (OMA), 1998

National Mention in the 13th Argentine Mathematical Olympiad, Argentine Mathematical Olympiad (OMA), 1996

LANGUAGES

ENGLISH, Advanced PORTUGUESE, Advanced SPANISH, Native